The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Knight of the Ribbon,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Twentieth Episode
The Shadow Eaters
I see you like listening
to music, eh, little sheep?
Let's go! Let's go for a walk!
- Let's go for a walk!
- Hey, friends!
Can I know where you are going?
Hello, Tink! We are
going to listen to a legend...
...from an old inhabitant of the
forest! Why don't you come too?
Oh, how wonderful!
I like legends so much!
Yes, I'm coming too!
Ouch, what a blow!
I really hurt myself!
Sure, I play the flute, but
don't look at me like that!
Alright, I will play
something sweeter.
What kind of story would
you like to hear today, children?
I would like to hear
a story about pirates.
No, pirates are not
interesting anymore.
I, instead, would like to
hear the story of a Princess.
Here I am! Wait!
Let me listen too!
Help!
My boy, there was no need for
you to rush over with such haste.
But I must continue
to watch the sheep.
After listening to the
story, I am forced to run off.
I took a little time off to
be able to hear your story.
Do you think it is right
to take this liberty...
...while you watch the flock?
- But it's only for a short time!
So, since it seems everyone
has arrived, I can begin.
- Yes, come on, begin!
- Good, good!
Today I will tell you the
story of the shadow eaters.
- Shadow eaters?!
- That's right, my children.
Do not be surprised,
now, by this term.
In fact, later, you
will understand why.
Well then. You must know
that once upon a time,
when there were few living
creatures on Earth,
it was natural that they could not
easily find each other.
As a consequence, it happened
that all living creatures...
...felt lonely.
None of them had friends
and many cried all day long,
so they were all depressed
and almost always sick.
So the Lord
began to worry.
...and thought that if he
provided them with friends,
they would return
to good health.
That was how the Lord
created shadows.
But one day the shadows disappeared...
...and men plunged back
into depression.
Then the Lord,
thinking it over and over,
found the solution once again...
...and attached the shadows
to the feet of men,
so they could no longer
be stolen...
...and finally they could have
friends forever.
Since then, shadows became
people's best friends,
but since then they also aroused the
appetites of the shadow eaters.
Good heavens! Those sheep
have wandered away from the flock!
What a hassle...! I have to
go and get those two back!
Look, there's something in
the lake! What could it be?
It's a monster!
It ate the sheep's shadow!
That must be
the shadow eater!
It might come towards us!
You'd better run away, children!
- Help! Help!
- Let's run!
Now it has seen us, guys!
We'd better run!
Tink, run faster!
Look, there's a house!
Listen to me carefully: let's not be
heard! Stay quiet and still!
Sapphire, the monsters are
approaching the house!
Quickly, Tink, bar the door!
- Tink, we must also bar
the windows! - Alright!
That window was left unbarred!
There it is!
Watch out, the roof is collapsing!
It's dangerous here! We must get out!
I'll try to stop it! You get out
while I am fighting!
Damned shadow eater,
I do not fear you!
I fell into a hole!
Good heavens!
I fell into an old well!
- Help! Mom! Help!
- Help!
What's going on down there?
Let's see...
- Come, we must escape!
- The monster took my shadow!
Help! Let's escape!
- Let's run! Let's run!
- Run! Run!
No! Damn it!
It ate my shadow too!
Those monsters are interesting:
the male eats
the boys' shadows,
the female eats the girls'!
I'll show them Sapphire!
Damn, he's already here!
We'd better run for it!
But where is my horse's head?
No! No, please!
Mine is a cheap shadow!
It's indigestible, can't you see?
Out of the way! Make way! Out of the way!
Tink, are you okay?
Hey, is there no one up there?
Tink, can you hear
me? Is anyone up there?
You're here! Thank
heaven! You're safe!
I thought something had
happened to you!
Now I'm relieved.
Thank you for saving me.
If it weren't for you,
I don't know what I would have done!
Well? What's going on now?
Why all this crying?
Tink, what on earth happened to you guys?
The monsters ate
our shadows!
Damn!
So they succeeded
The shadow-eating monster...
Let's see here...
Here it is, I found it!
It's him, right?
- Yes, it's really him.
- His name is Kagera...
...and he loves to eat the shadows
of humans and animals.
Originally, it seems he was a giant
snail that lived in lakes.
What will happen to the children whose
shadows were eaten by the monsters?
400 years ago,
the same thing happened...
and it says here that those children
died the next day.
They died?! Doctor, doesn't it say there
if there's a way to save them?
There is, but it's very difficult!
Let's take all the children of this
city to safety underground!
The monsters won't get them! I must
succeed in saving these children!
Look out!
The monsters are coming!
Where are the monsters?
- They are heading towards the city!
- I don't have much time!
The male monsters
eat the boys' shadows,
the female ones
eat those of the girls.
The monster that will want
Sapphire's shadow, what will it be like?
Damn, there's a female too!
Don't shoot! If they don't die,
they will destroy the castle!
We must try
to get them away from the castle!
- Yes, but how?
- I will act as bait!
I will get the monsters to follow me
up the mountain!
It's the only way
to drive them away from here.
- Prince, can I come with you?
- All right, come along.
It will be interesting to see which
monster is attracted by your shadow!
- What?!
- What? Don't you know?
The male monster
craves the shadows of boys,
the female, instead,
those of girls
We will see how they behave
in front of you.
Well, let's go now!
What's wrong, Prince?
Here they are!
Come on, monsters!
Try to take my shadow!
Interesting! The male monster
doesn't seem interested in you!
Help!
I'll take you to the
mountain! You'll be safe there!
Let's get out of here!
Run away, Nylon!
The monster is chasing me!
Nylon, don't run
towards the castle!
Now Kagera will go to the castle...
Kagera!
I am your enemy! Come
on, take my shadow!
This time Prince
Sapphire won't escape!
Go on, kill him! Good
monster! Try to catch him!
Like that! Yes, yes, good! Eat it!
I will help Sapphire!
Help, Tink!
Raise the drawbridge!
Please, Tink, recover
Everyone go take shelter
in the basement.
I will manage to destroy the monsters
and return your shadows to you!
My head! It's so heavy!
I have never seen
something so heavy!
My pinky!
It grabbed my pinky!
It hurts!
It was the female
that was hunting Sapphire!
- Just as I thought!
- There is a child in the park!
- What do we care about that child?
- But he is your son!
What?!
My son! It's really my son!
It's Plastic!
Quick, someone run
to help my son!
Oh, no! No!
My shadow!
Leave my shadow alone!
Oh, it's gone! What do I do,
now, without my shadow?
That monster has eaten
Plastic's shadow!
Come, Plastic! Don't cry!
Look, the monsters are sleeping!
My son! My son!
How are you, my son?
Are you alright?
Come!
What happened, Duralumin?
Even my son's shadow
has been eaten.
- Where are the monsters?
- They are sleeping in the garden.
I see! The sun is setting
and the shadow does not appear,
so they are resting.
Good, now is the right time!
- Oh, hello, Prince!
- Doctor, have you found...
...the way to get the shadow back?
- Yes, I have found it,
but this doesn't seem like a good
method. In fact, it's impossible!
We must use it anyway.
Tell me, what is it about?
The book says that
if we destroy the two monsters,
the shadows will return immediately,
but, unfortunately, the only one...
...who can succeed
in destroying them is the devil.
- The devil?!
- Yes, indeed.
The book says that
if we offer him as a sacrifice..
...what he desires most,
he will destroy the monsters...
...and will return all the shadows
to their place.
What can the devil desire
above all else?
Mephisto, Prince of Darkness,
listen to me!
I want to speak to you!
Come out! I am Sapphire!
Answer! Sapphire wants to speak to you!
Welcome, Sapphire!
Follow the light of the torch
and I will listen to what you have to tell me!
And so you must ask me
for a favor, isn't that right?
Ask for anything you desire!
Mephisto can do anything!
Even if Heaven were to burn
and the Earth were destroyed,
we devils will never die, as
long as a tiny flame exists!
Now tell me what you desire
and I will tell you my conditions!
You must destroy the
shadow-eating monsters.
Kagera? Even Sapphire seems
frightened by that monster!
All right, it is very easy for me.
But in exchange for
my help, I want to have...
Yes, I know what you want!
All right, I will give it to you!
You will have my boy's heart.
Sapphire, you are a
Prince truly very generous!
Hecate, destroy Kagera and bring me
Sapphire's male heart!
Instead of finding out
if Sapphire is a girl,
you attracted the monsters...
..and they broke my son's
little toe.
Look, the sun is about to rise!
With the sun,
the monsters will wake up!
Baron, Nylon, you are nothing but
a useless idiot!
- Yes, Yes! Yes! Yes!
- Grand Duke, behind you!
Here we are safe,
because there is no shadow.
Even in the water there is no
shadow, therefore they cannot eat.
Sapphire, help me get
Kagera out of the castle.
Hey, stupid Kagera! Come out!
It heard us!
Leave it to me! Let's run!
What do you want me to do?
- First, get off your horse!
- Alright!
This is the elixir that makes
the shadow stick to the ground.
Now let's leave quietly.
It's surprising how my
shadow is sticking to me.
In a little while, it will get
interesting. Look! Water for me!
Down!
Now, sugar for me!
Pour it in!
- What do you want to do?
- You will know soon.
Give me a spoon!
Stir the water!
What do you intend to
do with the sugar water?
This seems to me
a strange spell!
A broom for you!
Apply the sugar water with
this to the shadow of Kagera!
I wonder what use it
can be, this sugar water.
There, Hecate!
I did as you ordered.
Good, they have begun to
eat the shadow. Water, rise!
Now pay attention. You'll
see how I will destroy them!
They are eating
their own shadow.
Soon that sugar water
will become salt water.
My God!
Since Kagera is nothing but a
huge snail, it will melt with the salt.
Hooray! Hooray, we are saved!
The shadow is back! Hooray!
Hooray! How wonderful!
The shadow has returned! Thank
goodness! You are safe, my son!
Plastic, you are safe! You
are safe! How wonderful!
Hooray! Hooray! Plastic
is safe! Hooray! Hooray!
Hooray! Hooray!
The shadow is back!
Now, Hecate, as promised,
you can even take my heart.
All right.
A tree for me!
Sapphire, mount this one
and come with me!
Sapphire!
That is the devil! Sapphire
has been taken by the devil!
I couldn't wait
for this day to come!
- Sapphire, are you ready?
- No, Mephisto! Stop!
It's that angel!
Stay away from me!
If you want to take the heart of
Sapphire, you will have to fight us!
I destroyed Kagera
and the deal was...
...that I could take
Sapphire's heart!
I will give you my heart instead of
hers, and I will give it to you now! Hurry!
Go away!
My body is paralyzed!
Hecate, run! Cheat!
I am glad that you kept
your boy's heart, Sapphire.
We are both safe now!
Goodbye!
How wonderful Hecate is...!
Goodbye, friend! See you! Goodbye!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP